Rohan Ramani

509 E Stoughton Street Apt 101, Champaign, IL 61820

Champaign, Illinois

L 217-721-9972

☑ rohanramani06@gmail.com

Education

Masters of Science-Business Analytics

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

3.7/4.0 GPA

Information Systems & Marketing

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

August 2018 - May 2022

August 2023 - May 2024

About Me

A passionate data professional with experience working in fast-paced environments and the ability to deliver results. Worked on the Alexa sports team as a knowledge engineer tasked with improving and maintaining sports experiences for customers using Alexa devices, and have improved customer experiences reaching over 40M impressions.

Work experience

Data Science Consultant

February 2023 - June 2023

Credit Genie - Chicago, IL

Created queries and visualizations for customer churn analysis, improving customer retention of the company by 15% over 3 months

Modeled Data for internal company tools, helping executives understand customer data and take action on improvements to company app

Knowledge Engineer- Ontologist

June 2022 - January 2023

Amazon.com, inc. - Santa Barbara, CA

Created Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) jobs to establish metadata and publish sports videos on Alexa devices, with a projected customer impact of over 5M per video

Upgraded and maintained Basketball data collections in Alexa ontology graphs, creating more streamlined answering processes and faster answering times, improving customer experience for over 100,000 questions per day

Created the ability for Alexa to answer live roster questions in baseball, soccer and basketball events through ETL jobs and ontology adjustments, reaching over 5000 impressions per day

Data Engineering & Machine Learning Intern

June 2021 - August 2021

Treasure Data - Mountain View, CA

Worked on proprietary Customer Data Platform (CDP) to help clients solve various issues using datasets of 1M+ datapoints

Designed and created internal documents detailing and explaining the machine learning algorithms and processes occurring on the company CDP to create a better understanding for new hires

Created a Microsoft Teams notification system for clients needing to use the company platform to carry out data processes

Skills

SQL/Databases

Created and modified over 30 ETL jobs for Alexa databases to import raw data into Alexa engines, using 5M+ data points.

Wrote and customized SQL queries to investigate and translate the impact of Alexa answers on customers, impacting over 1M customer questions per week.

Python

Imported dataset of NFL team statistics from 2019 and used algorithms such as GridSearchCV and ElasticNetCV to investigate how important passing statistics are in relation to a team's win percentage and interpret the results. Used boosted tree models as well as imputation methods with libraries such as scikit-learn to optimize product placement in convenience stores based on sales figures around a calendar year.